<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>virtualization on Paul Czarkowski</title>
    <link>https://tech.paulcz.net/categories/virtualization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in virtualization on Paul Czarkowski</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tech.paulcz.net/categories/virtualization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Running KVM and Openvswitch on Ubuntu 12.10</title>
      <link>https://tech.paulcz.net/blog/running-kvm-and-openvswitch-on-ubuntu-12-dot-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tech.paulcz.net/blog/running-kvm-and-openvswitch-on-ubuntu-12-dot-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got an aging VMWare ESXi 4.0 server that needs to be replaced with something a little more modern and flexing.   Obviously at home I don&amp;rsquo;t need all the cool features that licensed VMWare comes with,  but I do want more than just the basic free version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few weeks of installing and testing alternatives  ( I&amp;rsquo;d really love to run openstack,  but it&amp;rsquo;s just not worth it at home for a single box ) I&amp;rsquo;ve settled on Ubuntu 12.10 server running KVM and Openvswitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After installing Ubuntu 12.10 I did the following to get KVM up and running&amp;hellip;   I cribbed this mostly from &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.allanglesit.com/2012/10/linux-kvm-ubuntu-12-10-with-openvswitch/&#34;&gt;blog.allanglesit.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving VMs from VMWare to KVM</title>
      <link>https://tech.paulcz.net/blog/moving-vms-from-vmware-to-kvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tech.paulcz.net/blog/moving-vms-from-vmware-to-kvm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m migrating from my old VMWare ESXi box to a new machine running Ubuntu 12.10 and KVM.    Not wanting to rebuild all of my VMs I set about trying to work out the best way to migrate the VMs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steps to make Windows migrate without Bluescreen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you migrate a windows box it&amp;rsquo;ll bluescreen due to the shock of so much hardware changing.   The following .reg hack will prevent this from happening by opening up access to a bunch of random system drivers.   Copy and run the .reg file in your VM before doing any further steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/4247499&#34;&gt;c:\temp\vmdriverhack.reg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Move your VM to shared storage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mounted an nfs partition to vmware from my freenas box and migrated the data across using the vmware datastore tools.   If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a NAS you could export a directory from your KVM server to achieve the same goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To move VMs in ESXi we click on the ESXi server, pick the Configuration tab,  click on &amp;lsquo;Storage&amp;rsquo; and then right-click on the datastore and select &amp;lsquo;Browse Datastore&amp;rsquo;.   Select the VM folder you wish to move and click the move icon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% img &lt;a href=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-R5x6JyT5x14/UMUkr4qNr4I/AAAAAAAAAHY/CYhOlizOLb8/s640/VMWare-move-1.png&#34;&gt;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-R5x6JyT5x14/UMUkr4qNr4I/AAAAAAAAAHY/CYhOlizOLb8/s640/VMWare-move-1.png&lt;/a&gt; %}&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>