<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Swarm on Paul Czarkowski</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/swarm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Swarm on Paul Czarkowski</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 13:00:42 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/swarm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>On Openstacks and Ecosystems</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2016/01/docker-swarm-on-openstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 13:00:42 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2016/01/docker-swarm-on-openstack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have recently had a number of lengthy discussions on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/zehicle/status/678736665792356352&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; about needing to focus on the ecosystem to extend the OpenStack IaaS user experience to something a bit more platform[ish].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote a post for &lt;a href=&#34;http://sysadvent.blogspot.com/2015/12/day-16-merry-paasmas-and-very.html&#34;&gt;SysAdvent&lt;/a&gt; this year on developing applications on top of OpenStack using a collection of OpenSource tools to create a PaaS and CI/CD pipelines. I think it turned out quite well and really helped reinforce my beliefs on the subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My buddy and future OpenStack Board member &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jjasghar&#34;&gt;JJ Asghar&lt;/a&gt; has been spearheading a new &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/Osops&#34;&gt;OpenStack Operators Project&lt;/a&gt;. I plan to contribute to this project by creating some examples of deploying tools that provide higher level services on top of the OpenStack IaaS layer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that I am very bullish about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://docker.com&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; ecosystem it makes sense that my first contribution would be focussed on running one of the several &amp;ldquo;Docker container scheduling/cluster&amp;rdquo; tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After playing around with a few of them, I settled on starting with Docker Swarm as its one of the easier to understand and run and doesn&amp;rsquo;t require any special tooling other than a recent install of the Docker binary to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To increase simplicity I chose to use Hashicorp&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://terraform.io&#34;&gt;Terraform&lt;/a&gt; and use only the most basic of the OpenStack services to ensure a fairly high likelyhood that it will run on most fairly up to date OpenStack clouds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the project&amp;rsquo;s suggestion I posted the Terraform files up to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/openstack/osops-tools-contrib/tree/master/terraform/dockerswarm-coreos&#34;&gt;osops-tools-contrib&lt;/a&gt; along with fairly comprehensive documentation on using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this and future work I plan to do to create similar examples will help the OpenStack Community out in some small way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>