<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>twitch on Paul Czarkowski</title>
    <link>https://tech.paulcz.net/categories/twitch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in twitch on Paul Czarkowski</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tech.paulcz.net/categories/twitch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming DevOpsDays Texas</title>
      <link>https://tech.paulcz.net/blog/streaming-devopsdays-texas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tech.paulcz.net/blog/streaming-devopsdays-texas/</guid>
      <description>I recently had the privilege to help organize DevOpsDays Texas 2021 a virtual event that we ran to try and scratch our DevOpsDays itch given that in-person conferences won&amp;rsquo;t be happening any time soon.
I had the misfortune of being the most experienced at OBS setup for live streaming and therefore was nominated as the person to figure out how to live stream the event to Youtube.
I chose to use Open Broadcaster Software (OBS) to manage the stream and Windows as the OS to run it on (OBS support is generally best on windows).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to broadcast to Twitch and Zoom with OBS</title>
      <link>https://tech.paulcz.net/blog/obs-broadcast-to-zoom-and-twitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tech.paulcz.net/blog/obs-broadcast-to-zoom-and-twitch/</guid>
      <description>Note: I have an updated, simpler version of this on Github with saved exports of profile and sources here.
 If you prefer a Video Tutorial, you can watch me screencast it on youtube, otherwise read on below.
  Recent world events (COVID-19) has completely turned the Developer Advocacy role on its head and many of us are scrambling to find new ways to effectively reach audiences remotely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming from Zoom to Twitch (or YouTube)</title>
      <link>https://tech.paulcz.net/blog/streaming-from-zoom-to-twitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tech.paulcz.net/blog/streaming-from-zoom-to-twitch/</guid>
      <description>Zoom meetings are great for a small number of people, and if you&amp;rsquo;re willing to buy a Webinar license you can also use it for a full on webinar (although there are some interesting restrictions to webinars, like you can&amp;rsquo;t have breakout rooms).
Twitch is a great streaming platform, originally used for streaming video games, its now more commonly being used to stream live coding and another technology related things that involve sharing your screen.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>