<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Registry on Paul Czarkowski</title>
    <link>https://tech.paulcz.net/categories/registry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Registry on Paul Czarkowski</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 10:22:22 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tech.paulcz.net/categories/registry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Flexible Private Docker Registry Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://tech.paulcz.net/blog/flexible-docker-registry-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 10:22:22 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tech.paulcz.net/blog/flexible-docker-registry-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>Previously I showed how to run a basic secure Docker Registry. I am now going to expand on this to show you something that you might use in production as part of your CI/CD infrastructure.&#xA;The beauty of running Docker is that you can push an image from a developer&amp;rsquo;s laptop all the way into production which helps ensure that what you see in development and your various test/qa/stage environments are exactly the same as what you run in production.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deploying a Simple and Secure Docker Registry</title>
      <link>https://tech.paulcz.net/blog/deploying-a-secure-docker-registry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 05:22:22 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tech.paulcz.net/blog/deploying-a-secure-docker-registry/</guid>
      <description>There comes a time in everybody&amp;rsquo;s life where they realize they have to run their own Docker Registry. Unfortunately there&amp;rsquo;s not a lot of good information on how to run one. Docker&amp;rsquo;s documentation is pretty good, but is verbose and across a lot of different pages which means having half a dozen tabs open and searching for the right information.&#xA;While it&amp;rsquo;s pretty common to run the Docker Registry itself with little to no security settings and fronting it with NGINX or Apache to provide this security I wanted to show how it can be done with just the Docker Registry.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
