<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Paul Czarkowski</title>
    <link>https://tech.paulcz.net/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Paul Czarkowski</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 09:04:08 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tech.paulcz.net/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume for Paul Czarkowski</title>
      <link>https://tech.paulcz.net/page/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 09:04:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tech.paulcz.net/page/resume/</guid>
      <description>Paul Czarkowski Principal Technologist (Developer Advocate) @ Pivotal Software
username.taken@gmail.com
http://tech.paulcz.net
https://github.com/paulczar
Work Permits : USA, Australia, UK/Europe.
Overview I am an experienced hands-on Architect / DevOps Engineer with a long history in Operations and Infrastructure Automation. I have a broad depth of experience across most IT and Operations related areas with strong experience in using and evangelizing DevOps tools and methodologies.
My current role at Pivotal has me primarily acting as a Developer Advocate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://tech.paulcz.net/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 09:04:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tech.paulcz.net/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Paul is an Infrastructure Engineer who has been doing IT and Operations for longer than he cares to admit and has worked across many industries, retail, game development, managed hosting, and more. He has worked in both very large and very small organizations.
As an avid Technologist he can be found tinkering with emergent technologies (hello running docker in production in 2014) and optimizing and codifying the operations of large legacy applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paul Talks about stuff</title>
      <link>https://tech.paulcz.net/page/speaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 09:04:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tech.paulcz.net/page/speaker/</guid>
      <description>An incomplete list of events that I&amp;rsquo;ve spoken at
2018    Date Event Title Location     Feb Cloud Foundry Meetup Singapore A DevOps guide to Kubernetes Singapore   Feb Devopsdays Charlotte A DevOps Guide to Kubernetes   Charlotte NC   March NYC Devops Meetup A DevOps guide to Kubernetes  New York, New York   April Devops Madison Devops is dead, servers are dying, and I don&amp;rsquo;t feel too great myself Madison WI   April CodeCamp Wellington Compliance as Code, Transform your security team with DevOps  Wellington NZ   April Longhorn PHP A PHP Developers Intro to Kubernetes  Austin TX   April Devopsdays Seattle Compliance as Code   Seattle WA   May Spring One Tour - Denver Emcee, Intro to Kubernetes  Denver CO   May Miami Kubernetes meetup Intro to Kubernetes  Miami FL   May VMWare PKS Roadshow Minneapolis Application Modernization and Replatforming with PKS/Kubernetes  Minneapolis MN   May VMWare PKS Roadshow Reston Application Modernization and Replatforming with PKS/Kubernetes  Minneapolis MN   May Spring One Tour - St Louis Emcee, Intro to Kubernetes  St Louis MO   June VMWare PKS Roadshow Chicago Application Modernization and Replatforming with PKS/Kubernetes  Chicago IL   June Cloud Foundry Meetup Tokyo Intro to Kubernetes Tokyo, Japan   June Opensource Summit Tokyo Kubernetes Day 2 Operations  Tokyo, Japan   June Linuxcon Beijing Successful Patterns for running Platforms  Beijing, China    2017 Sensu Summit  Sensu @ Bluebox - Video | Slides  2016 All Day DevOps  Serverfull computing - Video  OpenStack Summit Barcelona  InterOp Panel - Video OpenStack Compliance the DevOps way - Video  OpenStack Day Seattle  99 OpenStack clouds on the wall - Video  OpenStack Summit Austin  A PaaS for Continuous Delivery - Video  2015 OpenStack Summit Tokyo  Chef vs Ansible vs Puppet vs Salt - Video  DevOps Days Austin  Scout-A-Park a story of pragmatic dockerization - Video  OpenStack Day Seattle  Just enough OpenStack for Docker - Video  OpenStack Summit Vancouver  Docker Docker Docker Openstack - Video  Docker Austin meetup  Factorish - Video  2014 DockerCon14  Automated Chef cookbook testing with Drone.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>